VIRGINIE CORNU

linkedin.com/in/virginiecornu | contact.virginiecornu@gmail.com

(+33) 683 890 701 •

IT, BI & DATA MANAGEMENT

IT & Data professional with more than 10 years of experience in both technical and managing roles. Project and team management experience in Data analysis and Business Intelligence. Strong software development, data analysis and database administration skills. Detail-oriented, well organized and proficient at multitasking. Excellent interpersonal and communication skills.

SKILLS

- BI, Data Analysis & Data Management
- Team and Project Management
- Agile Methodology
- SQL Server, MongoDB

- Python, SQL, Javascript, C#, Php, AngularJS, Git
- Docker, Mysql, T-SQL, NoSql
- Tableau, Dataiku, SSAS, SSRS, SSIS, PowerBI
- IoT, Arduino, Data Science, Machine Learning

WORK EXPERIENCE

DATA & ANALYTICS MANAGER – Virtual Regatta (Online Sailing Game) – Paris, France

2019

Part-time during MBA, in charge of the creation of a new data department. Implement solutions to retrieve, store and analyze data and uncover new monetization opportunities.

MBA thesis: Impact of social interactions features on engagement and monetization in Free-to-Play mobile games. MongoDB, Docker, Python, Flask, Dash Plotly, AWS, Dataiku, Tableau.

BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE MANAGER - Betclic Group (Online Gambling) – Paris, France

2017 - 2018

Provided competitive intelligence and actionable insight to business departments as well as C-level management by identifying drivers of customer loyalty, brand awareness and website usage. Supervised a team of five BI developers and DWH architect based in France and Malta. Directed development and ongoing maintenance of a three-terabyte Data Warehouse, two cubes and a report platform providing over 150 reports to every departments of the company.

- Significantly improved system availability by reducing the loading time of the DWH by 50% (from 15 hours to 7).
- Implemented source control, release management and Agile methodology resulting in better visibility, communication and productivity.
- Reduced by 50% on-call hours by implementing monitoring tools and automating processes.
- Directed and implemented a games recommendation system in python to increase customer engagement.
- Ensured centralized information by writing and maintained KPI definitions documents and data dictionary.

PROJECT DIRECTOR - OpenField (Real-time data intelligence solution editor) – Paris, France

2016 - 2017

Coordinated the delivery of our data intelligence solution to our clients.

- Proxy role between our clients and our internal teams, providing day to day direction and statuses.
- Managed resources and oversaw finances to ensure projects progress on time and on budget.
- Supervised and coordinated functional and technical teams as well as external stakeholders.
- Product Owner role to technical team and set up Agile methodology in the company.

Responsible for the IT strategy definition and the implementation all technical areas.

- Defined product roadmap and technical architecture, led Project Management (Agile Methods)
- Developed websites, applications and a foreground extraction service (SaaS).
- Managed databases and BI solutions to follow revenue and engagement

Clothery - Your Dressing App • HUp! – The Digital Treasure Hunt

PRIOR EXPERIENCE

DBA SQL SERVER / BI DEVELOPER - Betclic Everest Group (Online Gambling), France - 2011 – 2015 In addition to day to day DBA activities, drove projects of data migration from Oracle to SQL Server for 2M customers in an international context and implement a full BI solution (DWH and MS BI tools).

SOFTWARE ENGINEER .NET – CONSULTANT - PSA Peugeot Citroën (Automobile Industry) - 2009 – 2011 SOFTWARE ENGINEER .NET / BI DEVELOPER - AIOI Motor (Toyota insurance company), France - 2007 – 2009

SOFTWARE ENGINEER / NLP INTERN - LIMSI – CNRS (The National Center for Scientific Research) - 2007 Natural language processing (NLP) role: Developed module for Named Entity Recognition. Conducted corpus analysis and developed machine learning algorithms in Java and python. Software engineer role: Developed a document management portal to researchers (Php/MySqI).

WEB DEVELOPER - Several positions (1IdNet, RATP) - 2002 - 2007

PERSONAL PROJECTS

JarJarBus - IoT Project - Connected device

2019

Internet of Things project to provide bus capacity to users and transportation companies in real-time. Won the third place of the connected car challenge organised by la Fabrique des Mobilités in 2019. JarJarBus

Posture Detector – *IoT Project* – *Connected device*

2018

Internet of Things project to prevent back pain by detecting bad posture and correct it immediately. Posture Detector

NaviShop - Personal project — Mobile application

2014

Conception and development of a hybrid mobile application to find shops in Paris subway and help optimize your travel time.

NaviShop

EDUCATION & COURSES

2019 – MBA Big Data Management and Decision Process – ESLSCA, Paris, France

2007 - MASTER I (4-years university degree) in Computational Linguistics - Paris VII University, France

2004 – BTS (2-years technical degree) in Web development – CESI, Rouen, France

2019 – Data Science Summer School (DS3) – Polytechnique, Paris, France

2016 – Datamining with Weka – MOOC – Waikoto University, New Zealand

2013 – Designing Business Intelligence with Sql Server 2012 – EduGroup, Paris, France

LANGUAGES

French (Native language) German (Beginner)
English (Fluent) Italian (Beginner)

ACTIVITIES & INTERESTS

Technology (Dev, IoT, AI)
Travelling (Europe, America, Oceania)

Music (Piano, Guitar, Violin, Drums) Sports (Badminton, Snowboard)